Guide to the Andrew Alpern Papers circa 1920-2015 PR 324
New-York Historical Society
- Series VII: 2018 Accrual - Reports by Christopher Gray, 1977-2009
  - 59 East 77th Street, 1980 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
  - 175-177 East 78th Street, 1979 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
  - 123 East 80th Street, 1994 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
  - 136 East 80th Street, 1979 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
  - 207 East 85th Street, 1980 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
  - 24 Gramercy Park, 1995 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
  - 530 Park Avenue, 1979 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
  - 863 Park Avenue, 1979 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
  - 120 and 125 Riverside Drive, 1979 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
  - 520 West End Avenue, 1986 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
  - 135 West 58th Street, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
  - 2 West 76th Street, 1995 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
  - [Photocopies] Real Estate Brochures, undated (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
    Includes:
    Reproduction of a 1914 promotional brochure for the John I. Downey Building Construction company.
    Reproduction of an undated promotional brochure for the Empire Building, 71 Broadway (built 1895-1898).
    Reproduction of a 1911 article about Churchill's Restaurant building, along with a letter from Andrew Alpern to Christopher Gray.
- Series VIII: 2018 Accrual: Reference Files for The Dakota: A History of the World's Best Known Apartment Building, 2015
  This series is made up of the reference files maintained by Andrew Alpern for the book The Dakota: A History of the World's Best Known Apartment Building, published in 2015. The files include images, articles, newspaper clippings, promotional materials and correspondence related to the book.
  - Apartments for Sale (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1)
  - Articles, Modern (Offsite-box 26, Folder 2-3)
  - Articles, Period (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4)
  - Britell, Richard (Offsite-box 26, Folder 5)
  - Channel 13 Interview (Offsite-box 26, Folder 6)
  - Clark (Offsite-box 26, Folder 7)
  - Floor Plans (Offsite-box 26, Folder 8-9)
  - Grant and Garrett Photos (Offsite-box 26, Folder 10-11)
  - Hardenbergh, Henry (Offsite-box 26, Folder 12-13)
  - Ho, Mia (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
  - Illustrations (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2)
  - Images (Offsite-box 27, Folder 3)
  - NYPL Talk (Offsite-box 27, Folder 4)
  - P.R. and Responses (Offsite-box 27, Folder 5)
  - Siegel Lawsuit (Offsite-box 27, Folder 6)
  - Singer (Offsite-box 27, Folder 7)
  - Van Corlear (Offsite-box 27, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 27, Folder 9)